CHRISTOPHE FOYER

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com
United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • France: (+33) 6-78-56-99-03
US and French citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

SUMMARY:

Mechanical Engineer with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, aerospace and energy engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

- CAD, FEA and CFD
- Prototyping and Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)
- Engineering Hand Calculations
- Embedded Systems and Software Development

EDUCATION:

Washington University in Saint Louis

Saint Louis, USA

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

Aug 2014 - Dec 2017

3.14/4.00 GPA

Study Abroad: - RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017) – Energy & Mechatronics - School for International Training, Iceland (Summer 2015) – Energy

EXPERIENCE:

Design Engineer

Temporary Works Design (TWD)

London, United Kingdom

Nov 2018 - Present

- Design of bespoke equipment and assemblies for civil engineering contractors using Autodesk Inventor
- Verification of structural parameters using engineering hand calculations and finite element analysis

Tata Steel Europe

Ijmuiden, Netherlands

Mechanical Engineering Intern – Student SWAT Team

Apr 2018 - July 2018

- Successfully built a proof-of-concept thermal simulation in Python reducing estimation error by 82.4%
- Estimating slab temperature within 21°C leading to potential savings of around one million euros per year
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

Domaine du Vivier Seasonal farm hand

Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work during the summer

PROJECTS:

[resume.cfoyer.com/#projects]

Senior Design Project - Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB for the development of a sunlight tracking circuit using Arduino. Proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%.

Electric Longboard

Oct 2016 - Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard. CAD, FEA, and part fabrication. Electrical powertrain design. Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations.

SKILLS:

CAD / FEA / CFD | SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, XFLR5

Programming Python, MATLAB, Simulink, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite wet layup (FG/CF), 3D-Printing, GD&T

Software / OS Microsoft Office Suite, LaTeX, Windows, Linux

Languages Bilingual English – French • Basic German and Icelandic

^{*}References available upon request